<!-- Plugin Configuration File. Read more: https://plugins.jetbrains.com/docs/intellij/plugin-configuration-file.html -->
<idea-plugin require-restart="true">

    <id>com.lazvaal.gradleglimpse</id>
    <name>Gradle Glimpse</name>
    <vendor url="https://github.com/LazVaal/gradle-glimpse">LazVaal</vendor>

    <description><![CDATA[
        <p><b>A lifesaver for Flutter developers migrating to AGP 8 and 9.</b></p>
        <p>Updating the Android Gradle Plugin (AGP) in a mature Flutter project often breaks the build due to hidden legacy native dependencies. Gradle Glimpse lives inside your <code>pubspec.yaml</code> to give you instant diagnostic insights.</p>
        <br/>
        <b>Features:</b>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Project-Wide Diagnostics:</b> Hover over the <code>dependencies:</code> key for a complete AGP upgrade verdict, showing the absolute maximum safe AGP version for your entire project.</li>
            <li><b>Instant Compatibility Checks:</b> Hover over any Android-enabled plugin in your pubspec to instantly see its AGP version and compatibility status.</li>
            <li><b>Transitive Dependency Tracing:</b> Uncover "hidden" native Android dependencies dragged in by pure Dart packages.</li>
            <li><b>AGP 9 Readiness:</b> Automatically detects critical AGP 9 blockers, such as the legacy <code>kotlin-android</code> plugin, missing namespaces, and outdated Java requirements.</li>
            <li><b>Flutter Auto-Healing Detection:</b> Intelligently warns you when Flutter is secretly patching legacy code at runtime.</li>
            <li><b>Real-Time Syncing:</b> Intelligently watches your file system and instantly updates diagnostics the moment you run <code>flutter pub get</code>.</li>
            <li><b>Customizable UI:</b> Toggle the visibility of Glimpse markers at any time via the View menu or right-click context menu.</li>
        </ul>
    ]]></description>

    <change-notes><![CDATA[
        <b>1.0.1</b>
        <ul>
            <li><b>New Feature:</b> Added a project-wide diagnostic summary. Hover over the <code>dependencies:</code> key in your <code>pubspec.yaml</code> for a complete AGP upgrade verdict.</li>
            <li><b>New Feature:</b> Added a visibility toggle. You can now hide/show Gradle Glimpse icons via the main <i>View</i> menu or by right-clicking in the editor.</li>
            <li><b>Bug Fix:</b> Fixed the "Infinite Cache" bug. Icons and diagnostic data will now instantly update when you save the file or run <code>flutter pub get</code>, without requiring an IDE restart.</li>
        </ul>
        <br/>
        <b>1.0.0</b>
        <ul>
            <li>Initial release: Full AGP compatibility scanning, transitive dependency tracing, and IDE hover UI.</li>
        </ul>
    ]]></change-notes>

    <depends>org.jetbrains.plugins.yaml</depends>
    <depends>com.intellij.modules.platform</depends>

    <actions>
        <action id="GradleGlimpse.ToggleIcons"
                class="com.lazvaal.gradleglimpse.ToggleGlimpseIconsAction"
                text="Toggle Gradle Glimpse Icons"
                description="Toggle the visibility of Gradle Glimpse AGP markers in the sidebar">

            <add-to-group group-id="ViewMenu" anchor="last"/>
            <add-to-group group-id="EditorPopupMenu" anchor="last"/>
        </action>
    </actions>

    <extensions defaultExtensionNs="com.intellij">
        <postStartupActivity implementation="com.lazvaal.gradleglimpse.PubGetListener"/>

        <codeInsight.lineMarkerProvider
            language="yaml"
            implementationClass="com.lazvaal.gradleglimpse.PubspecLineMarkerProvider"/>
    </extensions>

</idea-plugin>
